Yaser Ali Al Thahab

Email: yaser.ali32@hotmail.co.uk

Phone: +447427338054

Portfolio: https://yaser-ali.github.io/

Summary

A developer with more than half a decade of experience in the IT and Software development sector, development skills in programming, desktop-friendly software and web application. As a Software Developer, I enjoy solving problems, working on coding challenges and developing substantial, quantitative and readable code. A good attention to detail on the ways an application is developed such as its UI/UX (User Interface) design, functionality and interactivity.

Technical

Proficient knowledge in PHP, React, SQL and JavaScript, I have used and worked with a variety of programming languages and technologies such as Java, HTML5, JavaScript, Python, C++, ASP.NET, Laravel, SQL and C#. Extensive usage of version control systems such as GIT and SVN (Apache Subversion) and a Linux user.

Professional experience

Jan 2022 - July 2022

IT Developer – Kickstart Evans Group (Portfolio Home)

- A PHP API gateway application used for their purchase ordering system, in which it allows staff members of the company to accept purchase orders that are incoming from the company's Wayfair API system.
- Also Developed a PHP HubSpot notes API used for monitoring and keeping track of the company's notes, staff member's discussion with each other and list of companies they have a relation with.
- Used SQL to create query scripts, stored procedures and case statements in SSMS leading to stock intake and an inventory of products within their warehouse, allowing staff to see how much stock they need for a product and what seems to be out of stock or too much at stock as a result of running the query scripts.

Mar 2021 - Sept 2021

Software Developer – Kickstart role

Go Earth Ltd

- Published commercially viable database application with the use of MS Access and VBA.
- A WordPress application for establishing their subscription pass for which allows users to login and login to their commercially viable database application.
- Successfully documented and wrote all new processes for staff on the commercially viable DB application.

- Back-end scripting with the use of PHP and node.js to pre-register page.
- Adding features to the website in terms of design, interactivity, and functionality.
- Implementing the site's functionality, interactivity, and style on each page such as profile page, dashboard, and other stylish pages with the use of react.js, angular.js, jQuery, Bootstrap as well as foundation for making the site responsive and agile.
- Using React Native for mobile-friendly usages and allowing clients and solicitors to communicate more easily on their mobiles and smartphones.
- Using git, bower and gulp.js for tracking changes in the site and code changes

Education

02/23 - Current	Software development Bootcamp – Remote
01/2023 - Current	Ingeus Personal development course
2019 – 2020	Software Development B.S (Hons): Strong upper second (2:1) (67%).
	Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester.
2017 – 2019	Computing HNC / HND: Merit UCEN Manchester, Manchester
2014 – 2017	IT Computer Science OCR: Certificate. The Manchester College, Manchester, Northenden Campus.

Project(s)

Lawbid - https://lawbid.co.uk/

Multi award-winning legal tech site offering legal services by which clients provide legal requirements and appropriate solicitors fulfil those legal requirements. The website brings a very superior and quirky experience from its inventive UI, interactivity, and functionality. Now the website is used nationwide by clients and solicitors mainly.

Licenses & Certifications

1. Advanced Linear Models for Data Science 1: Least Squares – June 2021

Issuing Organization: JHU
License ID: WSTXRCHNFAE3
Grade Achieved: 91.40%

2. IBM Machine Learning with Python – March 2020

Issuing Organization: Coursera **License ID**: RA3AD5HZYP35

Grade Achieved: 87%